Now, he bets with other men's money!
ついに他人の金
禁断の3000万に手を出した坂崎
Sakazaki lays hands on the forbidden 30 million!
He dives back into a world of madness! Beyond all limits!
極限を超えた狂気の勝負 再開
Heaven's Fall, Man's Fall
負けられない
I can't lose!
おっちゃんの戦略は
もう風前の ともし火
Pop's plans are at their very edge.
It's like he's on a rope bridge about to collapse.
崩れかけた つり橋だ
見えている たどり着く前の崩落
He can see it! He can see himself fall before he makes it across!
それでも進むしかねえんだ
But still, he has no choice but to keep going!
そこに橋 希望がある限り
Following that bridge!
As long as he has hope!
He can't stop!
やめられねえよな
失っちまったんだから 全財産を
He's already lost all his money...
Even if he quits now! Even if that's the smart move!
たとえ今 やめたとしても
それが賢明だとしても
その後 おっちゃんに
どんな人生が待ってんだ
What kind of life will he have after that!?
今の仕事でもらった わずかな金で
あの暮らし
Living like that on the pittance he gets from his job?
勝つしかねえ　そうだ
He has to win!
Yeah!
勝つしかねえんだ
勝て おっちゃん
Win, pops!
橋を渡って成し遂げてくれ
Cross that bridge!
俺たちの悲願　リセット 再生を
For our wishes! Our hopes! Our rebirth!
Sakazaki's begun to bet the extra money he scraped up.
坂崎は急きょ用意したらしい
追加金を使い始めました
Perhaps it's about time for the block?
そろそろブロックの頃合いかと
何だ まだ動いてなかったのか
What?
You still haven't done anything?
はい 申し訳ございません
I'm sorry, sir!
どうせ追加の金は借金か
くすねてきた金
He has to have either borrowed or just pocketed that extra money.
そんなのに手を出すってことは
もう戻る気はないのさ
If he's dipping into it, he has no intention of stopping.
How shall I describe it?
言うなら
坂道を転がる暴走トラック
He's like a runaway truck, coming down the mountain.
The brakes have long since burnt away.
ブレーキは とうの昔に
焼き尽くしている
分かっていても止まらない
止めようがない
Even if he knows what's happening, he won't stop. He can't stop.
大破するまで
Until he wrecks.
ブロックを躊躇する必要はない
There's no need to hold back with the block.
I'll set it up right away, sir!
はっ では早速
What a pitiful sight. He's not even interesting enough to watch.
醜い　どうでもいい こんな奴は
I'm more worried about who he dragged in.
それよりも１匹
紛れ込んでいるじゃないか
名うてのギャンブラーが
That famous gambler...
敵は まだ動いていない
They haven't made their move yet.
決めるなら 今しかねえ
おっちゃん
It's now or never, pops!
The manager said...
店長が あの…
Go for it.
ブロック発動
The block activates!
ほれ
いけ 頑張れ　いけ
おっ？
何か入らなくなったぞ
He's not getting any in anymore!
クルーンに行ってねえ
全部 あの役モノに弾かれてる
Nothing's making it to the trays!
Everything's bouncing off the flippers!
今まで３分の１は通していた
クルーンへの番人 急変
The guardians of the trays had, until now, let one of three balls through!
But now, all that changes!
弾く　閉ざす
It shoots the balls back!
The path to hope now closes!
希望の道を
Dammit! They're up to something!
クソ　何か やりやがった
Pops...
おっちゃん
クソ
Dammit!
これや　このランプが
センサーになっとるんや
This light... It's really a sensor!
ひでえ　こんなんありかよ
This is terrible! I can't believe it!
ひどすぎる
It's terrible!
Pops...
おっちゃん　もういい やめろ
That's enough! Stop!
クルーンに行かなきゃ
いくら打っても全部 死に玉
If you can't even get to the trays, you're just wasting balls!
ま… 待てよ　これ…
Wait... This... This!
おー きた
え？
久々のクルーン
He finally got another one in the trays!
いけ
うおー
Go for it!
You can do it, pops!
いけるぞ おっさん
バカな　どうして
Impossible! How!?
To the right! He's bouncing them off the right and getting them in that way!
右… 右打ち
おっちゃん 右に玉を流し込んでる
しかし どうして
But why?
これは…
きた！
This is—
There it is!
また横道から！
開かれた奇跡の道筋
He got it in from the side again!
A path springs open, miraculously!
何てこった　ルートを外れた玉が
What!? He's bouncing misses off the wheel and into the trays!
車輪の回転で役モノの下を
くぐってクルーンに落ちている
あの表情　奴らにとっても
これは計算外なんだ
If they're making that face... That means they never expected this.
So...
ってことは ひょっとしてあるかも
Maybe he has a chance at the jackpot!
大当たり　大逆転勝利
He can turn it all around! A 600-million-yen miracle!
６億の奇跡
いけ　いけ
Go! Go!
諦めるな　諦めちゃダメだ
I won't give up! I can't give up!
吹いとるんだ 神風が
The divine wind pushes me on!
That wind brings my dead balls back to life!
その風が
本来 落ちるしかない死に玉に
吹き込んでくれている 命を
Another ten million!
もう1000万だ
確かに可能性はある
He has a chance.
だが あのブロック前の好調さとは
比べものにならない　おっちゃん
But the rate's still far lower than before the block.
Pops...
神にも慈悲があるだろ
The gods must have some shred of mercy!
これきり…
これきりってことがあるか
This is it! This is all I need!
あと１回 あと１回はあるはずだ
One more ball! One more ball!
３段目のクルーンに行くことが
行けば 行きさえすれば
If I can just land one more ball in the third tray!
今度こそ ねじ込む
こいつ 磁ビールで
This time I'll catch it with my magnetic beer!
しかし最初の数発こそ
通ったものの
But even though his first few balls made it,
その後は打てども打てども
after that, no matter how many he shot, the rest simply fell to the bottom of the machine!
空しく回収穴に のみ込まれていく
希望　消える 消える
His hopes fade! They fade!
希望の玉 １玉4000円
His balls of hope, at 4,000 yen each!
His nausea wells up, and!
こみ上げる吐き気
そして歪む 歪む
It bends! It twists!
溶ける 溶ける
It warps, it melts!
限りなく続く射精のような感覚
It feels like endless ejaculation!
死ぬ… 死ぬ
Dammit! Dammit!
The balls, they fly!
飛ぶ 飛ぶ
散る 散る
Only to fall!
光る 光る
It glows!
そして最後の1000万
And, he risks his last ten million!
おっちゃん
Pops...
発射 発射
He fires!
He fires again and again!
発射！
ある意味 桃源郷
In a way, this is his utopia!
破天　破漢　破滅
そして至福へのカウントダウン
The fall of heaven! The fall of a man! His ruin! A countdown to utter bliss!
見るにたえない至福
A bliss he can't stand to watch!
きたぞ おっさん
うん？
There you go, old man!
やった ２段目
いけいけ
You're at the second tray!
Go for it!
There it is! The third tray!
きた ３段目
ついに３段目　奇跡への入り口
He makes it to the third tray! Last stop before a miracle!
おっちゃん　入れろ
恐らく これが最後のチャンス
Make it in, pops!
This is probably your last chance!
頼む　入ってくれ
Please! Go in!
与えてくれ
Just make it!
もう一度 わしに
あの暮らし 日々を
I'll have my life back!
神様　神様　神様
God... Oh God, oh God!
おい 緩くなってきたぞ
Hey, he's losing it.
この１周で決まる
This is it!
ここだ
Here!
If I bend it here, I can win!
ここで引き寄せれば勝てる
勝つ
I'll win!
いけ　落ちろ
Go! Go in the hole!
ああ
マジかよ
Seriously!?
Aww man!
そんなんありかよ
Really!?
You were so close!
もう少しだったのに
惜しかった
That sucks!
What's with that!?
おっちゃん
Pops...
Pops!
おっちゃん
おっちゃん 大丈夫か
おっちゃん　おっちゃん
Are you okay, pops!?
Pops! Pops!
フフフ
おっちゃん… あ？
Pops...
ご友人は大丈夫ですか？カイジ様
Will your friend be all right, Kaiji?
こいつ どうして俺の名を
How does he know my name!?
You're...
あんたは？
ごあいさつが遅れました
Sorry I didn't introduce myself earlier.
I'm Ichijou, the manager here.
店長の一条という者です
以後 お見知りおきを
I'm quite pleased to make your acquaintance.
The manager?
店長？
さあ お諦めにならず
いま一度 勝負を
Now, now, you mustn't give up now. Take another try.
え？で… でも
But!
The can!
ちょ… ちょっと
マズい
Oh shit!
何か？
あ…
What?
最悪　最悪の展開
The worst! The worst possible thing which could happen!
バカな
Impossible!
さあ もう一勝負
Why don't you try one more time?
バカな　どうして…
おっちゃん
Impossible! Why!?
Pops!
ああ この玉ですか
Oh, these balls?
おい 今日はどっちだ？
はあ　真ちゅう製です
Which ones are we using today?
Brass balls, sir.
えっ 真ちゅう？
Brass balls!?
In order to avoid incidents with some of our more unsavory customers,
当店では よからぬことを
たくらむ連中への防衛策として
磁石に反応する鋼鉄製と
along with normal steel balls we have brass balls which aren't affected by magnets.
反応しない真ちゅう製を
使い分けています
さあさあ お客様　お気を確かに
Now, now. Go right ahead.
まだパッキーは残り600もある
You still have six million packy left.
大当たりの可能性は
残されています
You can still hit the jackpot. Go on, chase your dreams.
存分に夢を追いかけてください
我々は そのお姿を
心から応援する者です
We just love seeing players who aren't afraid to do so.
惨敗
この日 坂崎の手元に残ったのは
He's crushed!
At the end of the day, Sakazaki is left with only 6.38 million!
わずか638万
２時間あまりで4362万を失った
In what seems like only a moment, he lost 43.62 million!
チクショー
全部おとりだったんだ
Goddammit! We get hoodwinked! Bamboozled!
The A-setting schedule... Everything...
釘設定の予定表も何もかも
悔しい… 悔しい
I hate it! I hate it!!!
Dammit...
クソ
ほう そんなことがあったか
Oh, I see.
ええ　しかし坂崎も
あのカイジという男も しょせんは
Yes, but Sakazaki and that... Kaiji, did you say?
｢事が自分の思いどおりに
運ぶはずだ｣
と思い込みたがる甘ったれ
They're both naive enough to still think they were in control.
そんな輩に負けやしません
Of course I won't lose to men like that. I was about to handle things quite well.
何ら問題なく ねじ伏せました
カイジ君はそういう言葉で
くくれるほど一筋縄じゃいかんぞ
You can't just write Kaiji off like that.
Really, Ichijou...
それどころか ある意味 一条 君を
In some ways, Kaiji is far superior to you.
カイジ君は はるかに凌駕する
Be careful he doesn't trip you up.
まあ せいぜい足元を
すくわれぬよう気をつけることだ
The ponies!?
競馬？
４日後の競馬で
If we play the ponies in four days and work ourselves back up to 60 mil, we can try again!
残った金を6000万にすれば
やり直せる
本気で言ってんのかよ
Are you serious!?
まだ ここで一発 一発当てれば
We just need to take one more shot!
あと４日で残った金も
消えちまうのか
Take those four days and just take the money.
な… 何！
What!?
わりいこと言わねえから
残った金持って
Listen to me.
Take the money you've got left and find somewhere in the third world to go live.
物価の安い外国へでも
逃げたらどうだよ
縁起でもないこと言うな
Don't talk like that!
おい おっちゃん
Pops!
触るな　不吉 不吉　運が落ちる
Don't touch me!
Your bad luck's gonna rub off on me!
落ち着けって
Calm down!
昨日の玉
That's a ball from yesterday!
Hold it!
待てよ　ひょっとすると
That just might be—!
Inspiration flashes through Kaiji's brain!
脳裏を貫くひらめき　閃光
あ？
この玉 借りてくぜ
I'm borrowing this ball.
Huh? Borrowing? What?
え？借りてくって 一体…
I'm going back to that casino. There's something I need to know.
例のカジノに行ってくる
ちょっと確認したいことが
あるんでな
Kaiji, entering the casino in the evening,
夕刻 カジノに入ったカイジは
wanders around the Bog, as quiet as if yesterday had never happened.
昨日の熱気がウソのように
閑散とした沼の周りを漂い
And he stares.
そして眺め続けた 何時間も
For hours.
気がつけば朝　午前８時
When he looks up, the sun has risen.
It's eight in the morning.
ご友人が負けて
まだ一昼夜だというのに
It's barely been a day since your friend lost.
And yet you seem like you'd like to give it another try.
もう やりたそうな風情ですね
Not really.
別に
ちょっと失礼
Then, if you'll excuse me.
朝の日課でね
I have my morning tasks to attend to.
私と主任が日替わりで
こいつの釘調整をするんです
I alternate days with the maintenance man, adjusting the pins on this machine.
まあ 何も
毎日やらずともって話ですが
Well, they don't change every day so it's not every morning.
But money is money.
かかっている金額が
金額ですからね
店長である私が言うのは
はばかられるのですが
As the manager, I hesitate to say this,
設定は当分Ｃです
but of course it's usually set to C.
C?
Ｃ？
最もクルーンに到達しにくい設定
それがＣ設定
Setting C! The setting which makes it most difficult for balls to fall into the trays!
ノーチャンスです
No chance.
At least for the two weeks you have left on the outside, Kaiji.
少なくとも
あなたがシャバにいられる
ここ２週間ほどはね カイジ君
Seems like you know a lot about me.
随分と詳しそうだな 俺について
No, nothing else.
いいえ　知りませんよ 他には何も
I don't need to.
知る必要もないでしょう
薄汚い野良犬の素性なんて
Not about a filthy stray like you.
うわー
それホントの話か
So you think he'll run away?
Yeah.
ホントですよ
そんなバカな客…
何だお前 ここは立ち入り禁止だぞ
用のない奴が勝手に…
What's wrong with you!? It says, "Do Not Enter"!
If you don't have any reason to be—
—I have a reason.
用はあるさ
何？
What?
一体 何の用だ
Spit it out!
Son of a bitch!
貴様…
換金してくれ
Cash me out.
１つ おっちゃんの服に
紛れ込んでてね
I found this ball in the old man's clothes.
Don't give me that shit!
ふざけるな
よせ
Let him go.
は？
換金してやれ
We'll cash him out.
は… はい
Yes, sir...
クソ
Dammit...
ほら これでいいだろ
さあ出ていけ
Is that it?
Get out of here.
出ていけって言ってんだよ
I told you, get out of here!
そうカリカリしなさんなって
Jeez, pull the stick out of your ass.
Lemme have a smoke.
一服くらいさせろ
出てけ　今すぐとっとと出いてけ
Get out of here! Stand the fuck up and get out of here!
カイジ君　そんなに珍しいですか
この部屋が
Is this room really so intriguing, Kaiji?
何をたくらんでるか知らないが
I don't know what you're planning, but let me give you this advice.
悪いことは言わない
あの沼以外の
ギャンブルにすることだ
Try a game other than the Bog.
本来パチンコは
台を支配している店側が
The house controls everything about pachinko machines. It's always a losing bet.
100％勝つギャンブル
店が本気で出さないと
決めた台では決して客は勝てない
If we don't want it to pay out, the players aren't seeing a single yen.
かもしれねえな
かもじゃない
Maybe.
No maybes about it.
揺るぎない現実ですよ
Nothing but stark reality.
どうです　くだらぬ夢を見るより
How about this?
Forget those bullshit dreams and live for the moment.
あなたにとって貴重な今を
楽しんでは？
私の名刺を持って
こちらの店へ行けば
Take my card and go to this bar.
Drinks, food, everything will be on the house.
タダで飲み放題 食べ放題
You're going to be spending a long time underground. May as well enjoy yourself.
カイジ君がこれから送る
長い地下暮らしの慰みにぜひ
What the fuck are you doing!?
何をする 貴様
That feels even better than I imagined.
初めてやったが
思ったより気持ちがいいな
Especially if it's the card of a guy who just plain reeks.
それが鼻持ちならねえ奴の
名刺ってんなら
さらに格別　最高だ
It's awesome.
Son of a bitch!
野郎　貴様 ここから
無事に出られると思うなよ
You think you're getting out of here with your kneecaps!?
よせ
店長 いいんですか？
Back off.
Really, boss!?
I gave it to him. It's his to do with as he wishes, whether he should or not.
いいも悪いも
一度 渡した物をどうしようと
もらった者の自由だ
This is his last chance to show a little spine, after all.
たぶん これが
最後の意地ってやつなんだろ
Soon he'll be burrowing back down into the earth like a cicada.
これからセミのように
地の底へ戻る負け人間の
What a loser.
バーカ
Moron.
そんなチンケな名刺より
もっとデケえ土産を頂いたぜ
I walked out of there with something a lot better than his lame business card.
位置的には一番奥
The furthest one in.
あっ ６階 603号
The sixth floor. Room 603.
It's here.
ここだ
The power meter isn't moving.
電気メーターも動いてない
よし 空き部屋だ　やった
All right!
It's an empty room!
いけるかもしれねえ
I don't know if this'll work, but...
少なくとも
あの釘の森 第１関門は
That forest of pins... That first barrier...
突破できる
I've got it beat.
Kaiji grasps it!
カイジ　つかむ　人食い沼
He grasps the Bog's weakness! Its weakness!!!
その突破口を　突破口！
Proverbs of Kaiji Returns!
His hopes fade.
His nausea wells up.
It twists! It warps, it melts!
It feels like endless ejaculation!
In a way, this is his utopia!
The fall of heaven! The fall of a man! His ruin! A countdown to utter bliss!